{
    "id": "0c1895b079244b9299a24fa648f62675",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "There ……………………… an explosion in the city.",
            "description": "When there is no time reference, we use the present perfect to talk about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The terrorists …………………………. the bridge.",
            "description": "To blow  something up is to cause it to explode. ",
            "answers": [
                "blew up",
                "blew out",
                "blew off"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………………. the job by next Monday.",
            "description": "The future perfect is used to say that an action will have been completed by a particular point of time in future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will finish",
                "will have finished",
                "would have finished"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………… by the time I reached her place.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He didn’t let me …………………………..",
            "description": "Let is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "going",
                "go",
                "to go"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You haven’t …………………….. for your drinks.",
            "description": "Paid is the past participle of pay. ",
            "answers": [
                "payed",
                "paid",
                "pay"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The firemen were called in to ………………………… the fire",
            "description": "To put out is to extinguish. ",
            "answers": [
                "put off",
                "put out",
                "put up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "How beautifully …………………………..!",
            "description": "In exclamations, the subject goes before the verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "she sings",
                "does she sing",
                "she sing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Tell me what ………………………… in my room.",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary goes after the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "are you doing",
                "you are doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………… not pick up a fight with him.",
            "description": "Had better is used to give strong advice. ",
            "answers": [
                "had better",
                "have better",
                "had better to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We started early so that we ………………………. miss the bus.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will not",
                "would not",
                "should not"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "That dog of ………………………… has bitten me again.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "your",
                "you",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}